# Alex Bruce

# Computer Science

6/6 West Preston Street Edinburgh EH8 9PX

+447548108737

www.github.com/alexic0n alexbruce225@gmail.com www.alexic0n.com

#### Skills

Programming Languages: Java, Python, C, C++, Kotlin, SQL, Haskell and BASH.

Passion for cyber-security, focussed on studying cryptography and usable security throughout university.

Using Linux for a decade has given me a core understanding of how Linux systems work and how to interact with them.

Studied SQL systems and worked with PostgreSQL over the past few years, running databases for android projects and constructing complex queries.

Have built several apps over the last 3 years, within the Android Studio environment, including a large app using MapBox's API for navigation.

Experience working with networks, from web hosting to running the AI Brain for a chess robot on a remote server communicating with a Raspberry Pi.

Knowledge of OS's and low level programming (experience using MIPs).

Can speak basic German, studying for A2 exam this year.

Attention to detail, and I gain a lot of enjoyment from learning new skills.

# **Experience**

# **University of Edinburgh/** Summer Intern (IT Faculty)

May 2019 - July 2019

I worked for 8 weeks with the universities computer admin department. Responsibilities included deployment of new software and hardware, communicating changes with customers and fixing issues as they arose. A lot of the work was very independent and involved fixing problems in the network as they arose, often from remote locations.

I often had to work on systems used by those who weren't technically literate, and liaising with users like this forced me to appreciate how to approach situations where a user might not be completely easy with the work that is going on.

This job also required privileges on sensitive network, allowing me to experience the kind of issues that sys admins may face on a daily basis.

# **Unite Students/** Summer Receptionist.

July 2018-September 2018

I worked as a solo receptionist in a student halls facility during the summer of 2018. It operated as a hotel during this time, so the job involved coordinating with a large housekeeping team, and handling large quantities of cash/liaising with G4S for collections.

# JD Wetherspoon/ Bar Associate

June 2017- September 2017

Working in a very tight knit team through a very stressful period of the year was very beneficial for me. I learned a lot about how to deal with interpersonal issues within the team and with customers.

## **Education**

#### **University of Edinburgh / Computer Science BSc**

September 2016 - June 2020

I've been studying for my bachelors at Edinburgh, with a focus on computer security. I'm currently averaging 75% in exams (across 3rd year) and am predicted to graduate with 1st in June 2020.

My dissertation focuses on TLS and SSL, specifically focussing on the mitigation of vulnerabilities in the older versions with the TLS1.3 update. This will be published as a wiki for general academic or personal use within the cybersec community.

#### References

# **University of Edinburgh / Summer Intern**

Sajid Ashraf: Manager Email: <a href="mailto:s.ashraf@ed.ac.uk">s.ashraf@ed.ac.uk</a>

**Unite Students / Summer Receptionist** 

Iain Gillan: Manager

Phone: +443003038642